Guide to the Sean F. Killeen Lead Belly research collection, 1885-2002
Lead Belly research collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Sean F. Killeen Lead Belly research collection, 1885-2002.
Killeen, Sean
21.8
Publications, correspondence, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Research material, largely reproductions collected by Sean F. Killeen, documenting the life and career of Huddie William Ledbetter (Lead Belly), including correspondence with Harry Belafonte, Bob Dylan, Woody Guthrie, Burl Ives, Alan Lomax, John Lomax, Odetta, Pete Seeger, and Josh White. Also CD and DVD collections, "The Definitive Leadbelly" and "Leadbelly, Important Recordings 1934-1949".
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Lead Belly (Leadbelly), born Huddie William Ledbetter, was a blues musician and a prominent figure in the early years of the American folk movement. He was multi-instrumental, but mostly known for his skills on the 12-string guitar. In his early 20's Lead Belly left home and wandered through Louisiana and Texas earning a living by playing guitar whenever he could. He played with the blues singer Blind Lemon Jefferson for a short while.
Lead Belly's temper often landed him in jail. In 1915 he was sentenced to a chain-gang in Harrison County. In 1918, Lead Belly killed a relative and was sent to jail for a second time. After writing a song appealing to Governor Pat Morris Neff, Lead Belly was released having only served 7 of his 35 year sentence. While serving time in the 1930's for attempted homicide, Lead Belly was discovered by folklorist John Lomax and his son. Together they recorded hundreds of Lead Belly's songs for the Library of Congress. Lomax also used these songs for his book, "Negro Folk Songs as Sung by Lead Belly" (1939).
Upon his release, Lead Belly teamed up with John Lomax, gaining wide recognition within the recording industry. After a falling out with Lomax, Lead Belly continued recording his music. He was given a regular radio broadcast on Henrietta Yurchenko's show on WNYC in New York and toured in Europe. Lead Belly died in 1949 of lateral sclerosis.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Research material, largely reproductions collected by Sean F. Killeen, documenting the life and career of Huddie William Ledbetter (Lead Belly), including correspondence with Harry Belafonte, Bob Dylan, Woody Guthrie, Burl Ives, Alan Lomax, John Lomax, Odetta, Pete Seeger, and Josh White. Also CD and DVD collections, "The Definitive Leadbelly" and "Leadbelly, Important Recordings 1934-1949".
SUBJECTS
Names:
Killeen, Sean F.; Belafonte, Harry, 1927-; Dylan, Bob, 1941-; Guthrie, Woody, 1912-1967; Ives, Burl, 1909-1995; Killeen, Sean F.; Leadbelly, 1885-1949; Lomax, Alan, 1915-2002; Lomax, John A. (John Avery), 1867-1948; Odetta, 1930-2008; Seeger, Pete, 1919-; White, Josh; Lead Belly Society
Subjects:
Blues (Music) -- United States; Folk music; Prisons
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. General and geographical research
Series II. Miscellaneous Research
Series III.
Subseries IIIa. Individuals: correspondence and research
Subseries IIIb. Fan Mail
Subseries IIIc. Miscellaneous correspondence
Series IV. Publications, penitentiary research, and discography
Series V. Audio and Visual Materials
Subseries Va. CDs, Disks and Tape Recordings
Subseries Vb. DVDs, VHS and Microfilm
Subseries Vc. Photographs
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. General and geographical research
  - Accordion, 1980-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alabama, University of, 1992-1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Albany, University at, 1993-1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alfred University, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Allegheny College, 1983-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Allegheny College (cont.), 1993-1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Almanac Singers, 1942-1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alternatives Fund, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers (ASCAP), 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS, Lou Gehrig's Disease), 1992-1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Camp Anza, 1945-1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Apollo Theater, 1989-1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Arden, DE, 1947-2000 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Art, 1963-1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Art (cont.), 1991-1999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Associated Press, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Austin Record, 1971-2001 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - BBC (Felix Greene), 1938-1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Baltimore Archive, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Barker Center, University of Texas (John Wheat), 1935-2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Ben and Jerry's, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bennington College, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Berkeley, University of California, 1935-1997 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bibliographies, 1954-1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Biograph Records, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Black cowboys (George Blair), 1936-1996 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Black cowboys (George Blair) (cont.), 1936-1996 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Black soldiers, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Blues, 1988-1997 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Blues in the Schools, 1991-1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Blues Revue, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Blues Songbook, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Blues Songbook (2), 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Blues Songbook (3), 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bowie County, TX, 1926-1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bowling Green State University, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bravo network, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bridging Lead Belly (Rounder CD), 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Buffalo, NY, 1932-1998 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Buffalo, NY (cont.), 1992-1998 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Canada, 1990-1997 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Capitol Records, 1980-1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Carleton College, 1949-1998 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - CD-ROM, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Center for Black Music Research, 1992-1999 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Census -- Bowie Co., TX, 1910-1920 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Census -- Caddo Co., LA, 1870-1992 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Census -- Harrison Co., TX, 1900-1993 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Census -- North Carolina, 1971-2001 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Census -- North Carolina (cont.), 1991 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Centenary College, 1974-1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Cherokee Nation, 1962-1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Chicago, IL, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Children's concerts, 1945-1995 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Clarksdale, MS, 1915-1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Clarksdale, MS (2), 1910-1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Clarksdale, MS (3), 1992-1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cleveland, OH, 1948-1996 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Clubs, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - College concerts, 1948-1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Columbia University, 1944-1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Contracts, 1935-1997 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Cooperstown, NY, 1988-1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Copyright ( Lead Belly Letter), 1991-1999 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Cornell University, 1947-1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cornell University (2), 1947-1994 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Cornell University (3), 1947-1997 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Covers (songs), 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Dallas, TX, 1959-1998 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Dallas, TX (cont.), 1919-1996 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Dallas, TX history, 1892-1973 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Dance, 1997-1999 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Dirty Linen, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Drew University, 1949-1993 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Duluth, University of Minnesota, 1948-1994 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - East Tennessee State University, 1989-1999 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - East Tennessee State University (cont.), 1983-2000 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Elks Grand Lodge, 1931-1991 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Elmira, NY, 1946-1993 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Exeter, NH, 1948-1995 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Exeter, NH (cont.), 1948-1997 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Fan letters, 1944-1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - FBI records and correspondence, 1939-1998 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Film reviews, 1991-1995 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Film reviews (2), 1949-1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Film reviews (3), 1974-1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Folk Alliance, 1993-1997 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Folk Alliance (2), 1990-1998 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Folk Alliance (3), 1990-1998 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Folk Alliance, Memphis, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Folk Music Museum, Greenwich Village, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Folklore and folk songs, Southern, 1926-1994 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Ghostwriters, Inc. ( Lead Belly Letter printing), 1990-1998 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - "Goodnight, Irene", 1888-2000 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Government records (war rations, passport, marriage records, etc.), 1908-1997 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Grand Rapids, MI, 1948-1994 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Grave memorial controversy, 1949-1990 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - "Green Corn", 1895-1971 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - "Green Pastures", 1935-1948 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Guitars: 12-string, Stella, evolution, 1935-1999 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Guitars: literature, ads, companies, etc., 1890-1999 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Guitars, celebrity-owned: sales and prices, 1990-1999 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Guitars, Mexican: history, ads, construction, etc., 1977-1996 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Hamilton College, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Harrison Co., TX, 1894-1992 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Harrison Co., TX (cont.), 1991-1994 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Harvard University, 1933-1997 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Health (Lead Belly), 1942-1992 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Highlander Folk School/Research and Education Center, 1940-1995 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Hollywood, 1945-1995 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Hollywood Canteen, 1943-1991 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Huntsville, TX, 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Illinois (University of,) at Urbana-Champaign, 1941-1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - International Platform Association, 1948-1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Internal Revenue Service (IRS), 1991-2000 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Internal Revenue Service (IRS) (cont.), 1990-1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Ithaca (NY) High School, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "John Henry", 1929-1996 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Last Sessions, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Lead Belly Foundation, 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Lead Belly -- Relatives, 1878-1996 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Lead Belly -- Relatives (2), 1959-1994 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Lead Belly -- Relatives (3), 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Ledbetter name and family, 1939-2000 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Libraries, 1963-1999 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Library of Congress, 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Listings -- Directories, etc., 1994-1999 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Literary references, 1956-1995 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Louisiana Archives, 1935-1995 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Louisiana Catalog, 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Louisiana Folklife, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Louisiana - General, 1938-1974 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Louisiana State University in Shreveport, 1990-1996 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Macalester College, 1948-1994 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Majic Bus Civil Rights History Tour, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - March of Time newsreel, 1935-1996 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Marshall, TX, 1919-1997 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Masonic Order (Freemasons), 1947-1999 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - McAlpin Hotel, New York City, 1962-1999 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - McBooks Press: book proposal, etc., 1940-1997 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - McGill University appearance (Montreal, Canada), 1947-1996 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Media Ithaca Film and Video Festival: Lead Belly Sings to School Children video, etc., 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Mills College (Oakland, CA): periodicals, Lead Belly concert, 1945-1995 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - University of Minnesota -- appearance, 1948-1999 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Montreal, Canada, 1947-1999 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Montreal, Canada (cont.), 1947-1999 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Mooringsport, LA, 1992-1997 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Mt. Holyoke College (South Hadley, MA), 1935-1995 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Museum of Broadcasting (New York City), 1990 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Music Educators National Conference (MENC), 1990-1995 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Musicians, 1928-2000 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Musicians (2), 1928-2000 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Musicians (3), 1928-2000 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Musicians (4), 1928-2000 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Musicraft Records, Inc.; record companies, 1935-1995 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Negro Digest (letter), 1990 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - New York Council for the Humanities, 1989-1994 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - New York University -- appearance, letters, etc., 1920-1994 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - NPR correspondence, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Obituaries (Lead Belly) -- Black press, 1949-1990 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Obituaries (Lead Belly), 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Oklahoma -- "Twilight Time" appearance, etc., 1918-1998 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Pardon parody (Bush), 1998 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Paris -- Lead Belly appearance, Jazz musicians, etc., 1939-1997 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Paris (cont.), 1939-1997 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Peace Corps, 1991-1993 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - People's Songs, Inc., 1946-1994 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Philadelphia, PA, 1942-2000 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Photographers, 1938-1996 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Piano, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Pittsburg, PA, 1935-1996 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Politics, 1945-1977 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Post Office (non-profit bulk rate paperwork), 1993 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Programs, 1939-1993 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Providence (RI) Art Club, 1935-1994 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Publishers, 1991-1997 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Publishers (cont.), 1991-1997 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Publicity for Lead Belly Letter, 1991-1997 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Quotes on Lead Belly, 1945-2000 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Radio programs and scripts, 1940-1945 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Radio stations and programs, 1939-1997 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Record reviews (Lead Belly), 1937-1995 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Rochester (University of), 1935-1997 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Museum, 1950-1997 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Rock and Roll Hall of Fame (cont.), 1950-1997 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Roots and Rhythm, 1991-1995 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Rounder Records, 1988-1997 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - RSVP (Retired Senior Volunteer Program), 1975-1994 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Rutgers University, 1992-1995 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Ryko disc, 1995-1998 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - St. John's University (Minnesota), 1948-1997 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - St. Lawrence University, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Sam Adams School (Boston), 1945-1997 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - San Diego, CA, 1949-1997 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Sarah Lawrence College, 1946-1996 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Schomburg Clipping File, 1935-1990 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Shiloh Baptist Church (Mooringsport, LA), 1949-1996 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Shiloh Baptist Church (cont.), 1949-1996 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Scrap Book (book proposal), 1995-1997 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Scrap Book (cont.), 1995-1997 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Seneca Mist Graphics, 1991-1997 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Seneca Mist Graphics (cont.), 1991-1997 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Shanks (Camp), 1943-1995 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "Silver City Bound", 1933-1994 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Sing Out!, 1991-1994 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Skiffle, 1996-2000 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Smith College, 1943-1998 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Smithsonian Folkways, 1993-1998 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Smithsonian Folkways (2), 1990-1996 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Smithsonian Folkways (3), 1997-1999 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Songs (Lead Belly), 1895-1999 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Songs (Lead Belly) (2), 1895-1999 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Songs (Lead Belly) (3), 1895-1999 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Southwest Missouri State University, 1949-1997 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Stamp (USPS Commemorative), 1928-1998 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Statue (Jessie Pitts Jr.; Shreveport, LA), 1994-1996 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Swarthmore College, 1924-1999 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Swarthmore College (2), 1924-1999 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Swarthmore College (3), 1928-1999 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Swarthmore College (4), 1928-1999 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Tax exempt certification (Lead Belly Society), 1993-1999 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Tax info: New York State Charities Bureau (LBS), 1992-1996 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Tax returns (LBS), 1991-1996 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Tennessee Arts Commission: Folk Arts Program, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Texan Cultures, Institute of (University of Texas), 1935-1998 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Texas Tech University, 1949-1991 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Texas (University of), Austin, 1925-2001 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - T.O.B.A. (Theatre Owners Booking Association), 1980-1991 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Three Songs by Leadbelly, 1949-2000 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Tribute: 7 December 1999 concert (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Tribute: 7 December 1999 concert (cont.) (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Tribute: Memorial Concert (28 January 1950), 1950-1990 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - TRO: The Richmond Organization, 1980-2000 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Tulane University: Hogan Jazz Archive, 1984-1996 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Union 802 (American Federation of Musicians), 1939-1998 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - United States Information Agency, 1943-1994 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Unity (Camp), 1936-1997 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Unity (Camp) (cont.), 1936-1997 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Utah (University of), Salt Lake City, 1993-1997 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - V-disc, 1944-1998 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Video; Central Sun Co., 1991-2000 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Village Vanguard, 1940-1995 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Vision Shared (Folkways), 1993 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - World War II, 1945-1995 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Washington, D.C., 1942-1995 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Wayne State College, 1949-1998 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Wayne State University, 1946-1996 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Weavers, The, 1950-1994 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Wilbraham Academy, 1936-1994 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Wilton, CT, 1935-1998 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Winnetka, IL, 1946-1995 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Wisconsin (University of), Superior, 1948-1996 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Women, 1947-1996 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Y, 92nd Street (New York, NY), 1947-1997 (Box 9, Folder 34)
- Series II. Miscellaneous Research
  - Theses, Books, Articles: Louisiana, Slavery (1), 1933-1992 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Theses, Books, Articles: Louisiana, Slavery (2), 1933-1992 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Research 1 (Box 21, Folder 7-18)
  - Lead Belly Letter, 1990-1996 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Misc. photos, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Killeen’s Certificate of Appreciation from the Kiwanis Club of Ithaca, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Lead Belly Society business cards, address labels, Lead Belly Letter publicity cards, n.d. (Box 22)
  - Posters, photocopy of a scrapbook (Box 23)
  - Ken Kahn (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Bryan Mawr (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Esther Mae Scott (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Chronology, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Chronology, 1997 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Chronology, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Bibliography (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Cobain, Nirvana (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Insurance (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Research and articles (Box 25, Folder 11-18)
- Series III. Correspondence
  - Subseries IIIa. Individuals: correspondence and research
    - Abbott, Berenice, 1947-2000 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Abbott, Lynn, 1935-1995 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Allaire, Edith, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Anderby, Nils-Gunnar, 1992-1996 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Asbell, Bernard "Bernie", 1946-2000 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Asch, Moses "Moe", 1940-1998 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Asch, Moses "Moe" (cont.), 1940-1998 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Atkinson, Gary, 1957-2001 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Atkinson, Gary (cont.), 1957-2000 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Autry, Gene, 1972-1999 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Avakian, George, 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Aytch, Donald, 1991-1994 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Bachenberg, Eric, 1949-1997 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Baisley, Jessie Mae Ledbetter, 1975-1995 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Baldwin, James, 1963-1996 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Balliett, Whitney, 1947-1994 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Barnett, Lincoln, 1936-1992 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Barnicle, Mary Elizabeth, 1927-1995 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Basquiat, Jean Michel, 1985-1995 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Belafonte, Harry, 1956-1995 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Bell, Mike, 1950-1994 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Berkenfield, Alan, 1946-1991 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Biggers, John, 1973-1997 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Blacher, Dick, 1949-1996 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Blank, Les, 1992-1994 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Blum, Joe, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Borg, Greg, 1989-1995 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Boyd, Taleta "Panthy", 1995 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Branch, William, 1935-1996 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Brand, Oscar, 1946-2000 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Brown, Joe, 1964-2003 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Brown, Monty and Marsha, 1949-2000 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Brown, Phillip G. M. "Monty", 1989 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Burke, James Lee, 1971-1996 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Burns, Ken, 1944-2002 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Byington, Robert, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Byrd, Donald, 1994-2001 (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Capaldi, Jim, 1944-1996 (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Carr, Australia, 1908-1999 (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - Carr, Australia (cont.), 1908-1999 (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - Cash, Johnny, 1994-1999 (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Catlett, Elizabeth, 1944-2000 (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Charters, Sam, 1911-1996 (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - Choron, Sandra, 1962-1995 (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - Clapton, Eric, 1993-1995 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Cobain, Kurt, 1993-2000 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Cohn, Larry: Sony Records, 1946-1966; 1990-1998 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Cohen, Ron, 1990-1999 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Cooney, Michael, 1990-1997 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Cotton, Dorothy, 1990-1996 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Cowley, John, 1948-1985; 1990-1997 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Dalhart, Vernon (1), 1948-1973; 1992-1998 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Dalhart, Vernon (2), 1948-1973; 1992-1998 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Dalhart, Vernon (3), 1948-1973; 1992-1998 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Darling, Erik, 1994-1996 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Dart, Elisabeth, 1933-1934; 1994-1996 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Davis, Gussie Lord, 1888-1916; 1973-1980; 1990-2000 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Dexter Jr., Dave, 1959-1977 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Dickey, James, 1997-1999 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - DiGanci, Thomas, 1947-1949; 1993-1994 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Dillard, Bill, 1942-1949; 1990-1994 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Donegan, Lonnie (1), 1994-2002 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Donegan, Lonnie (2), 1994-2002 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Doors, The, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Douglas, John, 1995-1998 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Dvorak, Mark, 1993-1999 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Dyer-Bennet, Richard, 1942-1980; 1991-1998 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Dylan, Bob, 1979-1999 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Ellison, Ralph, 1990-1991 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Ertegum, Ahmet, 1941-1943; 1991-1995 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Evans, David, 1940-1941; 1993-1996 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Everhart, Bob: The Traditional Old Time Country Music Festival, 1993-1995 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Fabre, Michael, 1992-1997 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Fairbanks, Marjorie, 1949-1983; 1991-1995 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Faulk, John Henry, 1944-1980; 1991-1996 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Feld, Steve, 1988-1997 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Ferris, William, 1991-1999 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Filene, Benjamin, 1993-1995 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Finlayson, Keith, 19941-1996 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Fleming, Heidi, 1966-1996 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Flynn, Mike, 1991-1993 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Foote, Shelby, 1950-1989; 1991-1995 (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Fuller, Jesse, 1958; 1993-1995 (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Gates, Henry Louis "Skip", 1988-1998 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Gellert, Lawrence, 1934-1971 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Geremia, Paul, 1991-1995 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Gerlach, Fred, 1953; 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 4)